<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bci on Piotr Wittchen</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bci on Piotr Wittchen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 21:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brain-Computer Interfaces - Science Fiction or Reality?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-sci-fi-or-reality-oredev-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 21:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-sci-fi-or-reality-oredev-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had an opportunity to speak at the software development conference abroad for the first time. I visited Malmö in Sweden and gave a talk during the &lt;a href=&#34;http://oredev.org/&#34;&gt;Øredev&lt;/a&gt; 2018 conference. The main theme of the conference was Deus Ex Machina, so I decided to adapt to this topic and prepared presentation about Brain-Computer Interfaces, which is my interest since the end of my studies at the Silesian University of Technology where I wrote a Master Thesis about similar topic. Before the conference, I prepared the same presentation in Polish during the SAP Lunch Talks for the colleagues from my company in Gliwice, Poland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook is making solutions to talk from the brain – so do I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/facebook-is-making-bci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/facebook-is-making-bci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fbf8.com/&#34;&gt;F8 Facebook Developers Conference 2017&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook revealed its plans for the nearest years. Among different stuff, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.facebook.com/videos/f8-2017/f8-2017-keynote-day-2/&#34;&gt;keynote from the day 2&lt;/a&gt; was especially interesting for me. Speakers talked about connectivity projects increasing access to the Internet across the globe, different methods of human-computer interaction, virtual reality, and last, but not least &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain%E2%80%93computer_interface&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brain-Computer Interface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2017/facebook-is-making-bci/facebook-brain-interface.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super-interesting for me, because 4 years ago I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/polsl&#34;&gt;Master Thesis&lt;/a&gt; about Brain-Computer Interface for Mobile Devices at my university &amp;amp; published a few short articles about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/bci&#34;&gt;Brain-Computer Interface&lt;/a&gt; on this blog. You can also download my &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pwittchen.eeganalyzer&#34;&gt;EEG Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; Android app from Google Play Store. I also wrote another app called EEG Controller for communicating with the external world with brain and optionally with eye blinks. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t published. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll enhance and publish it in the future or I&amp;rsquo;ll create a better app for the similar thing. Of course, my apps are much simpler &amp;amp; less advanced than the Facebook plans, but still, both of them are aiming to solve similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting data in csv files generated by EEG Analyzer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interpreting-data-in-csv-files-generated-by-eeg-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interpreting-data-in-csv-files-generated-by-eeg-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people send me e-mails concerning &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pwittchen.eeganalyzer&#34;&gt;EEG Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; app. Usually they are not sure how to interpret or analyze results generated by the app and uploaded to Dropbox server. My app is quite &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; and simple, because it is additional project created during writing my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/polsl&#34;&gt;Master Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, which helped me to perform some experiments and analysis of EEG data. That&amp;rsquo;s why I didn&amp;rsquo;t focused on generating reports from gathered data. I focused only on reading and gathering data from MindWave Mobile device. In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to interpret data generated by EEG Analyzer and draw simple plots showing change of attention level, meditation level and blink strength.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EEG Analyzer - Android app</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eeg-analyzer-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eeg-analyzer-android-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently published my side project connected with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain%E2%80%93computer_interface&#34;&gt;BCI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroencephalography&#34;&gt;EEG&lt;/a&gt; technology in Google Play Store. &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pwittchen.eeganalyzer&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;unnamed&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/eeg-analyzer-android-app/eeg_analyzer_graphic.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pwittchen.eeganalyzer&#34;&gt;EEG Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; reads electrical activity of the brain with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroencephalography&#34;&gt;EEG&lt;/a&gt; technology and blink strength with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electromyography&#34;&gt;EMG&lt;/a&gt; sensor from NeuroSky MindWave Mobile device connected via Bluetooth to Android device. &lt;strong&gt;In order to use this application, you need to have NeuroSky MindWave Mobile device&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be ordered from &lt;a href=&#34;http://neurosky.com/&#34;&gt;http://neurosky.com/&lt;/a&gt; website. Direct link to the mentioned product: &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.neurosky.com/products/brainwave-starter-kit&#34;&gt;http://store.neurosky.com/products/brainwave-starter-kit&lt;/a&gt; Application has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain-Computer Interface for mobile devices - Master Thesis presentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-for-mobile-devices-master-thesis-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-for-mobile-devices-master-thesis-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I graduated from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.polsl.pl/&#34;&gt;my university&lt;/a&gt;. Below, you can browse my Master Thesis presentation about &lt;em&gt;Brain-Computer Interface for mobile devices&lt;/em&gt;. If you are interested in writing mobile Android applications communicating with NeuroSky MindWave Mobile device, you can check my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pwittchen/EEGReader/&#34;&gt;EEG Reader&lt;/a&gt; project on GitHub, which can be treated as a basis for more advanced projects. During writing my Master Thesis, I created two another projects using similar concepts. Mentioned code may be a little bit outdated comparing to the newest Android trends, but feel free to fork and upgrade it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain Computer Interface for mobile devices - introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-for-mobile-devices-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bci-for-mobile-devices-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently, I work on my Final Project and &lt;strong&gt;Master Thesis&lt;/strong&gt; at Silesian University of Technology in Gliwice, Poland (original University name in Polish: Politechnika Śląska). I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to choose unconventional topic, which will allow me to use the knowlegde I already have, extend it and learn something new. Topic of my thesis is: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brain Computer Interface for mobile devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain%E2%80%93computer_interface&#34;&gt;BCI&lt;/a&gt; is a topic, which is not completely discovered nowadays. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroencephalography&#34;&gt;EEG&lt;/a&gt; and BCI have their origins in 1924, but up to now, they don&amp;rsquo;t have so many real life applications. We can find only some experiments and simple games. Recently, companies, engineers and scientists started to focus on brain waves, so this topic is worth investigation and it may be the future of modern computing. In my project, I am going to use BCI for controlling mobile devices with Android OS. In my opinion, connecting brain to the smartphone can have really interesting outcome. Below, you can browse my presentation, which I have shown on my Final Project Seminar today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
